NILESH KOTAK

8575408650 • nileshkotak19@gmail.com • Hazlet, NJ 07730

Summary

Dedicated Architect and Interior designer with more than 4 years of experience. Pursuing master's in Architecture at New Jersey Institute of Technology. Led many interior and architectural projects from designing through execution to completion stage. Ready to tackle exciting new challenges in a similar role with a future employer.

Skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Graphics

Sketching, Hand Drafting, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Indesign Corel Draw, V-ray, Enscape.

BIM & 3D Modeling

Revit, SketchUp, Rhino, AutoCad

OTHER SKILLS

• Furniture Designing & Detailing

· Project management

- Teamwork
- Model making
- · creativity & problem solving

Experience

03/2022 - 01/2023

Intern Architect, Comito Associates, Newark, NJ

- Designed numerous blueprints using AutoCad for commercial, institutional, residential, and corporate projects.
- prepared various construction details for related projects in AutoCad.
- worked on permit sets.
- maintaining and responding to construction documents (Submittal and RFI's) for various projects.

11/2021 - 03/2022

BIM Specialist, Facilities Condition Assessment, **Center For Building Knowledge - NJIT**, Newark, NJ

- Responsible for scanning the entire Newark Public Schools facility with a Matterpot scanner to assess the condition of the building structure and documenting the data.
- Creating detailed 3D models of school premises on Revit using data developed by Matterport.

11/2019 - 08/2021

Senior Interior Designer/Architect, Designs Unlimited And Associates, India

- Led projects from conceptual phase through construction.
- visiting sits at various stages of construction to assess and assist agencies and vendors in meeting project needs.
- Worked closely with team members to deliver project requirements, develop solutions and meet deadlines.
- Developed 2D and 3D working drawings using AutoCad and SketchUp. Created graphical

presentation using Photoshop to discuss with clients to fulfill their needs.

01/2018 - 11/2019

Senior Interior Designer/Junior Architect, Sarthak Architects, India

- Consulted with clients to determine architectural preference to meet overall design goals and Implemented their needs from schematic design to construction document phase and installation.
- Designed floor plans, elevations, and 3D perspective views using AutoCad and Sketchup with physical material boards for both in-house review and presentation to client.
- Visited home sites when necessary to assess and fulfill customer needs.
- Reviewed project costs, budgets and adherence to schedules.

07/2017 - 12/2017

Interior Designer, Sarthak Architect & Interior Designers, India

- Prepared numerous blueprints for commercial and residential projects, and created 3D
 perspective views presenting various options during the design process of a specific space.
- Created custom design boards with attention to detail for visual representation, including samples of fabrics, wall finishes, and flooring.
- To assist my seniors and clients, I participated in the selection of furniture, materials, light fixtures, and other accessories.
- Researched concepts and followed industry trends to provide knowledgeable insight to clients.

01/2016 - 07/2016

Interior Design Intern, Ghoricha Associate, India

- Measured entire space and documented information to plan layouts.
- Created 150 blueprints for residential and corporate projects.
- Researched fixtures and furnishings aligned with project requirements and design style.
- Gathered price quotes from contractors and vendors. Went on various sites during construction phase with my senior to learn onsite management

Education And Training

Expected in 05/2023

Master Of Architecture, Architecture

New Jersey Institute Of Technology, Newark, NJ

07/2017 Bachelor Of Interior Design, Interior Design *APIED*, India

03/2013

Bachelor Of Commerce, Finance, Accounting, Economic, Management, HRs, *H.A College Of Commerce*, India